The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Eighth Episode
The Winged Horse
Where am I?
I recognize that one!
It's the ship that carries to Earth
the children who are to be born.
I get it: I'm in Heaven!
There, that's me!
What a naughty little angel I was!
I was always causing a lot of trouble.
But I just wanted to have fun!
Life, up there, is so monotonous!
These are the little
hearts of the children.
The Lord divides them
like this: boys and girls.
Come on, little one, open your mouth.
Those who swallow the
hearts blue will be little boys,
Those, on the other hand, who have pink
hearts will be little girls. Here!
I stole a blue heart
from the basket!
Hey, listen! Would you like
to be a little boy?
I don't know what advantage there would be
I will make a little boy out of you!
What hard work!
Finally, I'm almost finished.
Well, let's see...
You have a cute little face.
I will make you a beautiful little girl!
But I have already swallowed
a blue heart.
What did you say? It must have been
Tink who made this mess!
- Where did you hide?
- Forgive me, Lord!
You little rascal! Do you know that now,
because of you, that child...
won't know if he will have to live as a
little boy or as a little girl?
Go to Earth
and take a heart from him!
this is your punishment!
Thank goodness I was only dreaming!
But what I was dreaming
actually happened to me.
I'm so sleepy!
Tink! Tink, wake up!
Who is playing these pranks?
It's me, Tink!
Pegasus! I am glad to see you
after all this time! How are you?
What have you come to
do down here, on Earth?
In Heaven,
does the Lord remember me?
Is something wrong, Pegasus?
You have not yet done
what God wanted from you.
The Lord has lost His
patience and has tasked me...
...to take the blue heart of
Sapphire and bring it back to Heaven.
Wait a moment, Pegasus! It is
not my fault if I haven't taken it yet!
I've had a series of difficulties!
I know well
everything that has happened.
From Heaven I can see
everything that happens on Earth.
God's command is absolute.
I am forced to take over
your duties, Tink,
and you will never again
be an angel.
Wait, Pegasus! I...
How inconvenient it is to be a child!
If I had the little wings
I had in Heaven,
I could fly instead of walking!
Who knows, maybe I can still
fly! I want to try!
No luck! On Earth
it's a completely different thing!
- There are people!
- Look, a winged horse!
- How beautiful he is!
- Magnificent!
Look! How wonderful!
They say he lives in Heaven!
Oh, no! Pegasus is going to the castle!
Sapphire is in danger!
Your Majesty! Something extraordinary!
A marvel!
A horse flying
toward the castle!
What?! It must be Pegasus!
- He's almost above us!
- Let's go see!
It's Pegasus, the winged horse!
- What a magnificent beast!
- A unique sight in the world!
Perhaps he has come to bring
happiness to our kingdom.
It is said that Pegasus
always brings happiness.
What makes you think
that he has come for this reason?
A legend states
that the countries where Pegasus descends...
...become prosperous and happy,
so I hope he comes to us.
I didn't know this legend
Pegasus is flying away!
I must make him come here!
Sapphire! Sapphire!
I must catch up to him!
Tink! Help me make
Pegasus come back!
They say he brings happiness
with him!
- He brings happiness?
- Yes! A legend says..
...that wherever he
lands happiness arrives!
Pegasus will not bring you
what you are hoping for, Sapphire!
He has come to Earth to make
you become completely a girl!
What damn good luck to have heard
about the legend of the winged horse!
I've lost sight of him! I
must try to find him again!
Listen to me: Pegasus will
not bring you happiness.
Don't interfere! A
horse, even a winged one,
He can't do what you say! He
can't have gone too far!
Ah, there he is up there! He won't get away from me!
The moment I've been waiting for has arrived:
finally Sapphire is left alone!
Damn!
What could have happened?
Just as I was
about to capture the winged horse...
What? A net?!
I must find out who did it!
It's strange... I was sure
there was someone here!
- Baron Nylon! - Hello, Prince!
What are you doing in these parts?
I'm looking for a winged horse!
Have you seen it?
You must be joking?!
A winged horse?!
Yes! Pegasus, the horse that
brings happiness wherever he lands!
But I fear they've captured him.
Do you know anything about it?
No, Prince! I was passing by here
by chance and saw nothing.
If this horse
brings happiness,
I hope you find him
as soon as possible.
Goodbye, Prince.
It was easy to deceive
that stupid brat!
He has no idea that it was
me who captured Pegasus!
I've had a splendid idea!
It's not bad, this magical
house of the Grand Duke.
First I scared the brat with
the dynamite that I was given...
...and then I managed
to capture that horse.
I have never seen
such a splendid horse!
Nylon, are you really sure
that it will bring us happiness?
But of course, Baron Duralumin!
Let go of my nose right now!
Bites on my nose
do not make me happy!
You are an idiot!
Please calm down!
Don't take it out on me!
After all, I brought you
a one-of-a-kind horse!
I've had a great idea,
dear Grand Duke!
- Listen to me!
- What?
- Sapphire is...?
- Yes, yes!
Looking for that horse!
This is a great opportunity
to eliminate the Prince!
Good! Baron Nylon, you
are smarter than I thought!
Thank you for the compliment!
See? We just need to choose the
one that looks the most like Pegasus!
Not this one, not this one.
Definitely not: its muzzle
is a bit too rounded.
Of this other colt, however,
it's the eyes that I don't like.
It will have to be a
very elegant horse.
But they are all elegant like
this! Which one to choose?
I've finished! Admire
my masterpiece!
Yes, you've done a good
job. I admire your skill.
Now there is nothing left
for us to do but put this wasp...
...into the ear of the
fake Pegasus and wait.
I've anesthetized it, but
as soon as it wakes up...
...it will start
buzzing in its ear!
And when Sapphire sees the horse
on the ground, she will think that...
I wonder if I'll be
able to find Pegasus..!
He's on the tower!
Wait, Sapphire! Listen!
That Pegasus is fake!
That horse's wings are fake!
Listen! Sapphire, wait!
I managed to catch you!
Soon, the wasp should
wake up and then...
Come on, little horse!
Start flying!
Three, two, one... Here we go!
Hey, what are you doing?
What's happening to you?
Stop!
Don't jump like that, please!
Help!
Sapphire, hold on! Don't fall!
What can I do? Hold on, please!
Calm down, come on!
Don't fret, little horse!
He won't make it! Opal, help him!
Help! Help! Help!
Good heavens, he's plummeting!
Thank heaven! Sapphire! Sapphire!
Sapphire, how are you? Are
you alright? How do you feel?
It was this wasp
that made the horse bolt.
Someone put it in his ear
on purpose to get you killed.
This colt is not Pegasus. Who
could have set up this trick?
I'm sure it was Nylon who
played this other dirty trick on me!
But why does that damn
brat have to be so lucky?
I can never finish him off,
damn it!
- Damn it!
- Nylon, what are you doing here?
Hello, Prince!
I'm taking a walk!
I see you are well and healthy!
I'm glad!
- Goodbye.
- No, wait!
And now tell me: why did you
deceive me with that fake Pegasus?
Where is the real one? Speak!
But what are you talking about,
Prince?
- I assure you I know nothing about it!
- You are a liar!
It was you who captured him
and you are hiding him yourself!
If you think so, see for yourself
with your own eyes. Search for him!
Come, please! I will lead the way.
Look! Go ahead and look!
Here... and here! And here!
That's enough! I'll
never find him this way!
I will find out where you are
keeping him hidden, Baron Nylon!
And I will punish you!
Dear Opal, I still need
your help.
I am sure that with your sense of smell you
will succeed in finding where Pegasus is.
Go find him, please!
- This time you must not fail.
- Of course not!
I had already planned
the second move...
..and the next trap
will be perfect!
Do you know who we will
use this time? The real Pegasus!
- Are you Prince Sapphire?
- Yes, it's me.
- And who are you?
- I am a poor old man.
My brothers and I
live in the woods.
We saw a winged
horse injured in one leg...
..at the foot of the mountain..
...and we wanted to warn
you: maybe that horse is yours.
But Pegasus heals quickly
from his wounds.
- We'll see!
- He's onto us! Let's finish him off!
Let's get him!
Speak! Do you know
where Nylon put Pegasus?
- Yes...
- Then, if you value your life, you will lead me to him!
There he is!
It's really him!
Now you can leave!
There's the Prince!
Get ready! He's coming!
Spring the traps!
What's happening?
Stop! I'm your colleague!
Idiots! That's not the Prince!
- But it looked like him!
- Why are you such idiots?!
Here is Sapphire! Are you ready?
Pull!
Here I am, Pegasus!
- Sapphire, we're here!
- Be careful, Tink!
I will kill you!
I've wanted to meet you
in person for a long time.
Today I will take
your life, Prince!
Have at you!
I will cut off your head!
Like this!
That was a close call,
they almost killed you!
Pegasus!
You're safe, Pegasus!
Please, Sapphire, don't ride
Pegasus! It's dangerous!
Stop, Pegasus! Wait, Sapphire!
Listen to me!
Sapphire, get down! You don't know what
you're doing! It's starting to rain...!
Tink! Tink!
Sapphire!
Look, Opal: they are heading
towards that church on the mountain!
And now what do you want to do?
Stop, Pegasus!
Don't take the blue heart!
If you take it away from her,
she will be killed by the evil ones..
...who want to take over
her kingdom! Do you understand, Pegasus?
Sapphire must remain
with a male heart,
until she defeats the enemies
who lurk among her people!
That is why she prefers
to have a boy's heart!
Otherwise the people
will fall into the hands of the wicked!
Leave Sapphire as she is
until she has rendered them harmless!
If you insist on wanting to take from her
the heart I gave her in Heaven,
I will fight you to prevent it!
Tell the Lord that I myself will return
Sapphire's blue heart to Him
when in Silverland
peace reigns once again.
I am so happy!
You understood us, didn't you, Pegasus?
Pegasus!
Tell the Lord I'm sorry
for the trouble I've caused.
- Goodbye, Pegasus!
- His mission is over
Now he is returning to Heaven
and will report everything to the Lord.
Goodbye, Pegasus!
Tink, I've realized that happiness
is not thanks to a winged horse.
It must be earned
with sacrifices.
And I will try for my people
and for my country!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP